<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on about wbean1</title>
    <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on about wbean1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 08:38:27 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wbean1.info/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adversity, Motivation, and the Expanse</title>
      <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/adversity-motivation-and-the-expanse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 08:38:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbean1.info/posts/adversity-motivation-and-the-expanse/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling to come up with good topics to write about, but I think this one is broad enough to cover a lot of random recent thoughts floating through my mind.
Adversity One of my pet peeves of modern television culture is reality talent shows that spend a vast majority of the airtime milking/creating/curating people&amp;rsquo;s back-stories to highlight some adversity they&amp;rsquo;ve overcome in order to add a deeply personal or emotional attachment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping It Positive</title>
      <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/keeping-it-positive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 07:51:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbean1.info/posts/keeping-it-positive/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not an optimistic person by nature. There are a lot of things that can get me into a negative funk. Here are a few experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve had with positive &amp;amp; negative attitudes.
  If you don&amp;rsquo;t have anything nice to say, -
&amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t say anything at all.&amp;rdquo; I can still hear my mother saying this, primarily to my older sister who went through a bit of a &amp;ldquo;snotty teenager&amp;rdquo; stage in the early 90s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crazy Theories</title>
      <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/crazy-theories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 09:44:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbean1.info/posts/crazy-theories/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve sort of developed in my wild imagination, some bat-shit insane theories of the universe and everything. Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not actually as bat-shit insane as these might lead you to believe, and most of these are just sketches of thoughts rather than anything I fully subscribe to. Some fit together or overlay in disjointed ways, so its sort of hard to list out in a coherent way, but here goes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 08:04:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbean1.info/posts/writing/</guid>
      <description>Writing, and maybe Inspiration Like probably every human that is not a profesional writer, I find it fairly difficult to get into a writing flow-state. I then use this as an excuse not to write, and to think I&amp;rsquo;m bad at it. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been great at expressing emotions, and even when speaking frequently the words just seem to come from some place other than my brain.
I have recently been inspired to give this writing thing another go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Big Changes</title>
      <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/making-big-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 14:38:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbean1.info/posts/making-big-changes/</guid>
      <description>Ch-ch-ch-changes   I&amp;rsquo;ve lived a life of small, iterative changes. Both personally and professionally, these types of changes are generally safest. However, this year I&amp;rsquo;ve tossed this strategy out the proverbial window:
 New(er) House - Bigger, better, and more in debt. Complete with a home-office, this has been a great move. QOL++ New Job - I&amp;rsquo;m no longer a John Deere employee! Career moves are hard, but this opportunity with Pivotal was a big change in all the right ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Go Api Development</title>
      <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/getting-started-with-go-api-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 13:41:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbean1.info/posts/getting-started-with-go-api-development/</guid>
      <description>Prepare to enter a restart loop I&amp;rsquo;ve been poking at using go for a side project for about a month now, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to show for it.
Other than a vague feeling that &amp;gt;1000 other devs have recently made this same troublesome, looping sojourn, I&amp;rsquo;m left with not very much concrete progress.
Two images spring to my mind:
  Back in like 1996, I had a sweet geocities webpage where I fiddled around learning html.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operating a Platform</title>
      <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/operating-a-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 19:11:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbean1.info/posts/operating-a-platform/</guid>
      <description>So you want to run a platform&amp;hellip; Firstly, are you sure?
The as-a-service revolution is well underway, as this great article from Luke Kanies spells out. See also the momentous, if not dated, PaaS for Realists. Running your own anything anymore seems to be for the birds.
  But ok. You have your job cut out for you.
What are some of the requirements for running this thing you&amp;rsquo;re endevouring to deliver?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting Exp during the Open Source Explosion</title>
      <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/opensource-explosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 09:13:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbean1.info/posts/opensource-explosion/</guid>
      <description>The Open Source Explosion It is a pretty good time to be alive if you like tinkering with computer software. There is a literal ton (I weighed it, just trust me) of free-to-use, open source software out there to take up your days, and help you accomplish crazy things, crazy efficiently.
As you can tell from my resume, I make use of a lot of this software professionally:
 ansible apache httpd apache tomcat cloudfoundry collectd concourse docker elasticsearch grafana haproxy influxdb jenkins kibana logstash memcached mysql / mariadb nagios nginx packer postgres prometheus puppet samba sonarqube terraform  But what makes an open source project &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 15:15:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbean1.info/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>An introduction of William Bean Hello not-so-anonymous internet user-agent. I am William Bean, a human living on Earth in the nation of the United States of America, in the state of Illinois, in the area of the Quad Cities.
I do web app technology stuff for a little company called John Deere.
Most of my hobbies also involve tinkering with technology. I enjoy pinball, poker, &amp;amp; biking with friends. You might also find me at the Quad Cities Linux User Group.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
