<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>about wbean1</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on about wbean1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:56:06 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Life is a Journey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lifes-a-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:56:06 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lifes-a-journey/</guid>
      <description>Life, the universe, and everything. Life&amp;#39;s a journey, Not a destination. -- Aerosmith Ain&amp;#39;t about how fast I get there Ain&amp;#39;t about what&amp;#39;s waiting on the other side It&amp;#39;s the climb -- Hannah Montana 42 -- Deep Thought (Douglas Adams) OK. So we&amp;rsquo;re done with the witty quotes for this post. Lets have some Deep Thought about Life.&#xA;! Disclaimer, this next part of the post was written like a year ago and sat unfinished on my hdd&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conscious Ramblings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/consciousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 07:28:51 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/consciousness/</guid>
      <description>I think therefore I am Theres really not much more &amp;ldquo;proof&amp;rdquo; of existance existing besides this saying from some dead guy. Consciousness may be the most &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; thing; it could determine whether this existance is a single-player role-playing game (RPG), or a massively multiplayer online role-playing game (MMORPG). Its perhaps impossible to have &amp;ldquo;proof&amp;rdquo; that other people besides yourself have the same level of conscious thought as you; however I find that to be very likely given there is so much philisophical writing on consciousness that I can identify with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blueprint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blueprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 14:43:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blueprint/</guid>
      <description>So this is more or less the Blueprint I follow for my life. This is a somewhat sarcastic response to Bryan Johnson (entrepreneur)&amp;rsquo;s Blueprint, which I find 50% fascinating &amp;amp; 50% utterly ridiculous.&#xA;Just Keep Running Being healthy and feeling physically good are one of the few things I feel ok being a bit selfish about. It may sound obvious, but you will likely only have one body for your entire life; you should probably prioritize taking care of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carrying Comfort</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/carrying-comfort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 20:10:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/carrying-comfort/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t Get Too Comfortable Let me preface this entire ramble by admitting that I&amp;rsquo;ve recently binge watched all 9 seasons of History Channel&amp;rsquo;s Alone. In case you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with the show, the run-down is that ten contestants are dropped off in separate locations in a remote wilderness with 10 chosen items, and compete for who can stay out alone the longest, all while filming it themselves. Honestly, this concept appealed to me much more before watching the reality of what happens even to seasoned professionals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collecting Wins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/collecting-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 21:50:39 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/collecting-wins/</guid>
      <description>All I Do is Win Win Win I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up a few nuggets of knowledge over the years, from either friends or random internet bullshit. Anyways, these come from various sources, but all have rang true to me. I present them here in no particular order.&#xA;The Monty Hall Problem - This is basically any Computer Science major&amp;rsquo;s intro101 to probability theory. For some reason it blew my mind. Its all about revealing information and how that changes probabilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Old</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/getting-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 10:15:47 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/getting-old/</guid>
      <description>No one likes getting old. However, I&amp;rsquo;m a bit surprised at how much I dislike getting old. Let me count the ways.&#xA;Your concept of self must fundamentally evolve or shift as you age. I used to think of myself as a sharp, young, whipper-snapper who would surprise you with critical energy when needed most. I don&amp;rsquo;t know that I&amp;rsquo;d use many of those same words anymore. And that is sort of sad &amp;ndash; its almost as if that former self has already died.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 16:21:34 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pain/</guid>
      <description>It has been said, in various ways, that &amp;ldquo;life is pain&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few experiences with this over the past year that cause me to reflect on this. Should make for a great story, so strap yourself in, here we go.&#xA;Pain that you overcome So prior to this year, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a relatively pain-free life. I&amp;rsquo;d been lucky, like a child of the summer. My experience with pain was basically with standard stuff you overcome relatively quickly and forget about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Things You Own</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-things-you-own/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 08:22:10 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-things-you-own/</guid>
      <description>A Story About Camping My current employer does this awesome thing where every Friday in July &amp;amp; August is given off to the entire company. No one works those days. They call it &amp;ldquo;R&amp;amp;R Fridays&amp;rdquo;, and it is amazing for work-life balance.&#xA;The first R&amp;amp;R Friday I drove up to a small town ~45min away and bought a ~10 year-old used popup camper.&#xA;I have a lot of memories from my childhood of playing with my cousins and sisters at campgrounds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adversity, Motivation, and the Expanse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/adversity-motivation-and-the-expanse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 08:38:27 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/adversity-motivation-and-the-expanse/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling to come up with good topics to write about, but I think this one is broad enough to cover a lot of random recent thoughts floating through my mind.&#xA;Adversity One of my pet peeves of modern television culture is reality talent shows that spend a vast majority of the airtime milking/creating/curating people&amp;rsquo;s back-stories to highlight some adversity they&amp;rsquo;ve overcome in order to add a deeply personal or emotional attachment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping It Positive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/keeping-it-positive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 07:51:30 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/keeping-it-positive/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not an optimistic person by nature. There are a lot of things that can get me into a negative funk. Here are a few experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve had with positive &amp;amp; negative attitudes.&#xA;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have anything nice to say, -&#xA;&amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t say anything at all.&amp;rdquo; I can still hear my mother saying this, primarily to my older sister who went through a bit of a &amp;ldquo;snotty teenager&amp;rdquo; stage in the early 90s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crazy Theories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/crazy-theories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 09:44:53 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/crazy-theories/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve sort of developed in my wild imagination, some bat-shit insane theories of the universe and everything. Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not actually as bat-shit insane as these might lead you to believe, and most of these are just sketches of thoughts rather than anything I fully subscribe to. Some fit together or overlay in disjointed ways, so its sort of hard to list out in a coherent way, but here goes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 08:04:48 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/writing/</guid>
      <description>Writing, and maybe Inspiration Like probably every human that is not a profesional writer, I find it fairly difficult to get into a writing flow-state. I then use this as an excuse not to write, and to think I&amp;rsquo;m bad at it. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been great at expressing emotions, and even when speaking frequently the words just seem to come from some place other than my brain.&#xA;I have recently been inspired to give this writing thing another go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Big Changes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/making-big-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 14:38:04 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/making-big-changes/</guid>
      <description>Ch-ch-ch-changes I&amp;rsquo;ve lived a life of small, iterative changes. Both personally and professionally, these types of changes are generally safest. However, this year I&amp;rsquo;ve tossed this strategy out the proverbial window:&#xA;New(er) House - Bigger, better, and more in debt. Complete with a home-office, this has been a great move. QOL++ New Job - I&amp;rsquo;m no longer a John Deere employee! Career moves are hard, but this opportunity with Pivotal was a big change in all the right ways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Go Api Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/getting-started-with-go-api-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 13:41:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/getting-started-with-go-api-development/</guid>
      <description>Prepare to enter a restart loop I&amp;rsquo;ve been poking at using go for a side project for about a month now, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to show for it.&#xA;Other than a vague feeling that &amp;gt;1000 other devs have recently made this same troublesome, looping sojourn, I&amp;rsquo;m left with not very much concrete progress.&#xA;Two images spring to my mind:&#xA;Back in like 1996, I had a sweet geocities webpage where I fiddled around learning html.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operating a Platform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/operating-a-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 19:11:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/operating-a-platform/</guid>
      <description>So you want to run a platform&amp;hellip; Firstly, are you sure?&#xA;The as-a-service revolution is well underway, as this great article from Luke Kanies spells out. See also the momentous, if not dated, PaaS for Realists. Running your own anything anymore seems to be for the birds.&#xA;But ok. You have your job cut out for you.&#xA;What are some of the requirements for running this thing you&amp;rsquo;re endevouring to deliver?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collecting Exp during the Open Source Explosion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/opensource-explosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 09:13:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/opensource-explosion/</guid>
      <description>The Open Source Explosion It is a pretty good time to be alive if you like tinkering with computer software. There is a literal ton (I weighed it, just trust me) of free-to-use, open source software out there to take up your days, and help you accomplish crazy things, crazy efficiently.&#xA;As you can tell from my resume, I make use of a lot of this software professionally:&#xA;ansible apache httpd apache tomcat cloudfoundry collectd concourse docker elasticsearch grafana haproxy influxdb jenkins kibana logstash memcached mysql / mariadb nagios nginx packer postgres prometheus puppet samba sonarqube terraform But what makes an open source project &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 15:15:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>An introduction of William Bean Hello not-so-anonymous internet user-agent. I am William Bean, a human living on Earth in the nation of the United States of America, in the state of Illinois, in the area of the Quad Cities.&#xA;I do web app technology stuff for a little company called John Deere.&#xA;Most of my hobbies also involve tinkering with technology. I enjoy pinball, poker, &amp;amp; biking with friends. You might also find me at the Quad Cities Linux User Group.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
