<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>about wbean1</title>
    <link>https://wbean1.info/</link>
    <description>Recent content on about wbean1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 13:41:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wbean1.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Go Api Development</title>
      <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/getting-started-with-go-api-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 13:41:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbean1.info/posts/getting-started-with-go-api-development/</guid>
      <description>Prepare to enter a restart loop I&amp;rsquo;ve been poking at using go for a side project for about a month now, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to show for it.
Other than a vague feeling that &amp;gt;1000 other devs have recently made this same troublesome, looping sojourn, I&amp;rsquo;m left with not very much concrete progress.
Two images spring to my mind:
 Back in like 1996, I had a sweet geocities webpage where I fiddled around learning html.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operating a Platform</title>
      <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/operating-a-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 19:11:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbean1.info/posts/operating-a-platform/</guid>
      <description>So you want to run a platform&amp;hellip; Firstly, are you sure?
The as-a-service revolution is well underway, as this great article from Luke Kanies spells out. See also the momentous, if not dated, PaaS for Realists. Running your own anything anymore seems to be for the birds.
  But ok. You have your job cut out for you.
What are some of the requirements for running this thing you&amp;rsquo;re endevouring to deliver?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting Exp during the Open Source Explosion</title>
      <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/opensource-explosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 09:13:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbean1.info/posts/opensource-explosion/</guid>
      <description>The Open Source Explosion It is a pretty good time to be alive if you like tinkering with computer software. There is a literal ton (I weighed it, just trust me) of free-to-use, open source software out there to take up your days, and help you accomplish crazy things, crazy efficiently.
As you can tell from my resume, I make use of a lot of this software professionally:
 ansible apache httpd apache tomcat cloudfoundry collectd concourse docker elasticsearch grafana haproxy influxdb jenkins kibana logstash memcached mysql / mariadb nagios nginx packer postgres prometheus puppet samba sonarqube terraform  But what makes an open source project &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>https://wbean1.info/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 15:15:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wbean1.info/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>An introduction of William Bean Hello not-so-anonymous internet user-agent. I am William Bean, a human living on Earth in the nation of the United States of America, in the state of Illinois, in the area of the Quad Cities.
I do web app technology stuff for a little company called John Deere.
Most of my hobbies also involve tinkering with technology. I enjoy pinball, poker, &amp;amp; biking with friends. You might also find me at the Quad Cities Linux User Group.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>